They've given the order to kill
all the sick here and shut the place down.
Hong Eun-jo.
Halt!
His Highness is in there.
Don't worry.
There will be no more arrows coming.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Thank you.
Brother.
Sorry I'm late.
Your Highness.
Your Highness!
It's you again.
It seems my thoughts keep slipping out.
Don't make me regret
not killing you last time.
Is this funny to you?
So many people nearly died,
all because of your family's greed.
Go.
I don't feel like seeing
anyone's blood today.
Why don't you just punish me?
Your brother will be punished
for commanding this, and you…
have already been punished.
Did you know
you almost killed Physician Hong?
What?
You were here.
How's the wounded one?
The arrow didn't go in very deep.
You saved the people at the camp.
Thank you so much for coming.
Of course. You called.
Let me clean up the rest.
If you stay too long, you might--
Why is this
stuck so tight?
Listen to me, will you?
I can be pretty stubborn too.
At least wear the face covering properly.
If you're done nagging, you can go.
- Let me fix it for you.
- I'm good.
I'm saying this as a physician.
You know the entire pharmacy would panic
if you caught even a cold.
It's quite bold of you to do this,
given where we are.
You're right.
I'm usually a coward.
Running away is my specialty.
And you ran into a hail of arrows
just like that?
Next time, stick to your specialty.
Run away.
I wish I could, but I can't help it.
When I'm with you, I become fearless.
What?
This is because
you brought up the folk tale and all.
You made me too brave.
Are you saying it's my fault?
Yes, you keep giving me courage.
This is why I need to be
selective about people.
What did you just say?
I guess just the two of us are going.
What about His Highness?
Is he spending the night here?
He says he has to protect her tonight.
Oh, the power of love.
I once yearned for a woman just as deeply.
Is she gone now?
She's high up now.
I'm surprised.
By my devoted love?
I get that a lot.
People say I'm too handsome for that.
You had a woman?
That's why you're surprised?
That's offensive!
Don't you have to go back to the palace?
People at your residence
must be looking for you.
That's why I sent Dae-chu.
Are you sure you want to do this?
Spending the night
in the forest isn't easy.
It can't be that different.
We're on the same land of Joseon
under the same sky.
It's nice out here.
It's dark,
black,
and pitch-dark.
I wonder if Dae-chu will be really late.
Right.
I wonder.
Is he already back?
Did you hear that?
That's definitely the sound of a wolf.
Do you
know that wolf?
How would I know any wolf?
You said you saw one around the annex.
That's a wolf I wish I didn't know.
Then I'll scare it off.
I'm sure it's a wild dog looking for food.
Go away.
Stay back, or you'll get burned.
It's leaving.
That's right. It left.
This is
just like when you said
the rain was a thunderbolt.
I'm not
very good with water.
I'm sure you are.
I really am not.
Ever since I was little.
Why?
I once fell into a lake.
How did you get out?
I woke up at the Royal Villa.
Apparently, someone saved me
and carried me to the shore.
They saved your life.
My mother looked for them everywhere,
but she couldn't find them.
You must've been so scared,
all alone in the water.
I don't remember it
because I was too young.
If you ever need to be near water,
let me know.
You?
I'm a pretty good swimmer.
My mother said
that I was a fierce swimmer in her womb.
I guess I'm a natural in the water.
I'm serious.
Are you laughing at me?
I was just smiling.
I always have been.
If the feelings are too deep to let go of,
please leave Joseon
for Eun-jo's sake.
It looks tasty!
It looks tasty, doesn't it?
This is the only thing we can give you.
It was made by a healthy child
who was born and is living here.
So it's safe to eat.
This is precious food. How could you…
We received some rice from Gil-dong.
Who? Gil-dong?
Rice cake, Gil-dong,
there's a lot to digest.
Are you all right?
So, Gil-dong rose from the dead?
He'll soon be immortal.
That's what rumors are like.
Now do you see how I felt?
You're listening in so naturally.
Naturally. I know it already.
I'm his lord.
If I lose my job, I'll be an idler.
And you'll break your parents' hearts.
What are you talking about?
I'm saying I will keep my mouth shut.
I refuse to be
your partner in crime though.
Are you backing out now?
I've backed out.
How about both of you back out?
Sister! Brother!
Geum-dol.
Here.
What's that, kiddo?
It's a talisman.
All the children born here
wear this talisman
with the word "life" written on it.
It's meant to protect them
from the illness their parents carry.
Why did you bring them, Geum-dol?
You can have them.
I don't need them anymore.
- What?
- Animals don't need them.
Who said that?
Bun-i did.
She said that
even if we had been wiped out yesterday,
no one would have cared
because we're just animals.
So you and Brother can have them.
Of course you don't need it.
Kiddo,
you can live a good life
without it.
Really, Sister?
Of course.
We will dispatch a post horse
to the Royal Villa
to inform His Majesty
of the vile acts you committed yesterday.
Go ahead
if you have the nerve to bear the cost.
Grand Prince Dowol?
Why does he want me to come this far?
What's this?
Who set a trap here?
Of course it's me. I called you here.
Your Highness,
how could you treat a scholar like this?
I'm only treating an animal
like an animal.
Pardon?
Mong-sil.
Get him.
Your Highness, what is this about?
Good boy.
Your Highness, please don't kill me.
That's exactly
what people at the leper camp shouted.
How…
How did you…
Im Seung-jae admitted that
he ordered the leper camp burned down
in this letter of confession.
He's the eldest son of Chief Secretary Im.
It would be difficult for me
to dismiss him over this alone.
I was told it would actually be easy.
The leper camp he ordered burned down…
His Highness was there.
Grand Prince Dowol?
This is a grave matter.
The Grand Prince was nearly killed.
Tell His Highness that this affront to
the royal family will not go unpunished.
Did you know
you almost killed Physician Hong?
I can't even enter my own house?
You must think you're a great physician,
thinking you can save
all the sick in Joseon.
I'm sorry that arrow didn't kill me.
Last night,
you took away something
from a child
whose whole world was the leper camp,
and whose only wish
was to live a long life
with his ailing mother.
Do you know what that was?
How could you treat a human being
like an animal?
Because…
those are lowlifes.
That's what the world says.
But not my world.
To me, everyone is precious.
LIFE
Young Master.
Grand Prince Dowol,
how dare you dismiss me?
Once Father is back…
Young Master.
Black Sword!
What is this scoundrel even saying?
Do you think I will do as you say?
No. I think you must.
How could you miss catching him
every single time?
I apologize.
He said he'd put an arrow
through my throat tomorrow.
What do we do?
Do you have an idea?
This is the idea?
I don't like it either.
It's only until we catch him.
Young Master, your lunch is ready.
Bring it in.
- Oh, dear!
- Seung-jae.
Seung-jae.
How did he even…
It says, "Tomorrow, it'll be
steel at your throat, not cotton."
Why don't you just do as the letter says?
I would rather die than disgrace myself.
I can't do that to those lowly animals.
"I have wronged you
beyond forgiveness."
"It was no way
to treat a human being."
"You are not animals."
"I am."
"It is I,
Im Seung-jae."
Why are you all crying?
Don't cry.
Now I've seen everything.
I can't believe
a nobleman apologized to us.
Really? That's unusual.
Right?
And it happened twice.
Twice?
The State Tribunal's secretary
came back and said
that he was the younger brother.
Was his name
Jae-i of the Im family, by any chance?
Yes.
He said he didn't deserve forgiveness.
He said that,
whether with fists or arrows,
we should pay them back twice over.
It sounded harsh,
but it sounded like a heartfelt apology.
Do you want me to pay you back too?
Come on. Stab me.
You've already been slashed
dozens of times.
I don't need to add to it.
Take off the cotton cloth.
I'll apply some medicine.
I almost killed you.
I would stab you a hundred times,
but I will accept
your apology.
And this is the Hyeminseo.
We save people's lives here,
not kill them.
And I'm a physician.
Your brother will be punished
for commanding this, and you…
have already been punished.
So this is my punishment.
Punishment?
Having you worry about my wound
when I almost killed you.
Having you show me warmth
and give me false hope.
That's my punishment.
Are you just leaving like that?
What did you mean by that just now?
The Grand Prince knew
that I was getting this punishment.
I don't understand.
Here's my hand.
What are you doing?
What are you looking at? I'm hurt.
- Are you doing this on purpose?
- Yes.
- Why?
- Because I want to.
Let go of her hand.
I wonder how it would look
if the most exalted Grand Prince
were to lose his composure and go mad.
You won't get to see that.
Because he's just like me.
He's hurt.
He's a patient.
What are you doing?
Go on, hit me.
Even in war,
the wounded are not to be attacked.
He's here to apologize.
If you're done here, leave.
And seek a private physician if possible.
You're making me pettier and pettier.
What?
What's that?
I heard something interesting
at the constabulary.
I think I read somewhere that Gil-dong
used cotton as an arrowhead.
Is this the one?
It does look like
Gil-dong's arrow that I saw,
but Gil-dong is dead.
Where did you get this?
I picked it up in my own room.
You must have heard
about the rumor that Gil-dong was the one
who sent rice to the leper camp.
Get to the point.
My conclusion is
that Gil-dong
is alive.
And he's still around Your Highness.
The investigation into Gil-dong
has been closed.
The Chief Secretary has agreed too.
I knew it.
You go to such lengths to protect him.
Gil-dong must be someone dear to you.
I'm almost jealous.
Don't do anything silly, Im Jae-i.
Stop.
That concludes my report, Your Highness.
I'm the secretary of the State Tribunal,
Jae-i of the Im family.
We'll speak again
regarding Gil-dong's case.
What happened?
I didn't want to use
the arrow as a threat,
but I couldn't just sit by and do nothing.
They're the ones who took it away.
Took away what?
Basic human dignity.
I can't let them take that away too.
If anyone at the leper camp
had actually lost their life,
I might've done something even worse.
It's good that they got it back.
But next time, ask for my help.
Don't get your hands dirty
threatening people.
"Threaten"
isn't quite the word I would use.
It was more like a suggestion.
"Listen to me while I'm being nice"?
I see. That's respectful enough.
Anyway,
don't worry.
The Chief Secretary's second son
won't be able to find any more evidence.
And in Joseon--
I know.
No one would ever suspect a woman
of being a thief.
Except for one person.
You're the only one in Joseon who knows.
Right.
So if I disappear from Joseon,
then no one will know anymore.
I must head to the constabulary.
I left my horse there.
Your Highness.
These are all the records about Gil-dong.
Make sure nothing about Gil-dong
is spoken of.
If you find anyone other than Im Jae-i
chasing Gil-dong,
make sure she's protected.
What about Your Highness?
Are you going somewhere?
I'm doing what I'm best at.
Running away.
Hong Eun-jo.
I was terrified when he found out,
but now I'm glad that he knows.
How funny is that?
You keep giving me courage.
I'm just smiling.
I always have been.
Right.
This is
my proposal.
I totally forgot about it.
Where did I lose it?
I heard that Im Seung-jae was dismissed.
Chief Secretary Im will be shocked
to hear this when he's back.
Grand Prince Dowol is behind all this.
He had an aide
deliver Im Seung-jae's confession to me.
That person?
Here's the report on the rumors
surrounding Gil-dong, as requested.
Look into how Grand Prince Dowol
is involved with the leper camp.
Yes, ma'am.
My niece as His Highness' bride?
If you must say no,
I'll try not to be too disappointed,
for old time's sake.
I would never.
I will send a letter to my niece.
If we get caught up in formalities,
His Majesty will step in.
Do you have something in mind?
A little bit of
romance?
Where is Her Majesty?
What are you doing here?
Your Highness.
Her Majesty asked me
to play some music, so…
She was here just a moment ago.
It seems like
I'm supposed to be carried away
either by your music or your beauty,
and end up completely smitten.
What's next?
Running into you by a secluded watermill?
It seems like
I'm supposed to lose my cool here and…
At least don't make it so obvious
that Her Majesty is behind this.
The two of them
have pretty classic tastes.
I would call it outdated.
They believe coincidences mean destiny.
Oh, a dullard.
Wait. He's from…
May I ask you a question?
That's why the three coincidences
were overlooked.
What do you mean?
Nothing.
I heard about the unfortunate incident
at the leper camp.
Though it was for a short while,
I was engaged to someone from that family.
What they did is
truly infuriating.
Since you're saying
you finally realized it,
congratulations
on escaping the Im family.
Move on from that engagement.
What about you, Your Highness?
Are you moving on from that woman?
I'm running away from her.
What did you just say?
I will leave Joseon.
Why?
A trip disguised as studying abroad.
You'd feel more at ease that way
than if I stayed close to His Majesty.
It's a hit, Your Majesty!
Your Majesty is truly
an exceptional hunter.
I'm concerned for Your Majesty's health.
Our return to the palace
has been delayed by ten days.
For tomorrow's hunt,
we'll go farther than Mount Dogo.
I hear there are tigers there.
Your Majesty,
thousands of people
have been displaced for this hunt.
And tomorrow,
the number will grow tenfold.
It's suspicious that
he suddenly wants to study abroad.
Is Hong-si still on sick leave?
Well…
There is something
I have not yet told you,
fearing it might upset you, Your Majesty.
How dare you bring an outsider
into the palace disguised as a court lady?
So, you refuse to tell me who Hong-si is?
Well done.
If anyone asks, keep silent,
and never speak of her.
His Majesty must not learn of this.
Sister, what are you looking for?
Geum-dol.
Have you seen
an envelope this big?
Maybe it's not here.
Is it important?
It's something
I want to keep only to myself.
Brother.
How did you…
I went to Hyeminseo to talk to you,
and you weren't there.
So I knew where to go.
Hey, my brother.
Were you talking about something fun?
Yes, Sister said
she wanted to keep something--
Geum-dol!
Your…
Your mother is looking for you.
You should hurry back.
His mother is waiting.
I'll take him to her.
Come on. Let's go.
All of a sudden?
The weather has been nice these days.
You're right.
I'll remember this for a long time.
This time we're in now.
So…
What is it that you wanted to say?
Right.
Don't worry about Im Jae-i.
I made sure all evidence
tied to Gil-dong is gone,
so he won't be able to interfere anymore.
I'm worried about me, not you.
If you get caught,
I'll get in trouble too.
We're partners in crime.
I don't usually like to brag,
but I learned my archery
from my lord, the former Minister of War.
You must be close to him.
Yes.
When I was little,
my lord and I
went to the market together every year.
It felt like a special outing to me.
It was only later that I found out
it was the day before
he was dispatched to the battlefield.
It's yeot!
Do you want some?
If he had died in any of those battles,
that special outing would have been
my last day with him.
He said he didn't want
my last memories with him to be sad.
That's the kind of man he is.
And he taught me archery
so I could protect myself and the family
when we're left alone.
And now, you're even looking out
for your neighbors.
Even if I'm not in Joseon--
Is that…
Hello.
What are you doing?
I almost missed it.
Today, we have Maeguigut.
MAEGUIGUT: A FOLK RITUAL
PRACTICED FOR GOOD LUCK
We should make wishes.
Can I get two, please?
I'm sorry.
I only have one left.
Don't worry about me. I don't make wishes.
Why don't you give it a try?
As they say,
the heavens are always by our side,
closer than we think.
Their hearing might be
worse than we think too.
Then I'll say my wish out loud and clear.
I'll take the last sky lantern.
Make sure you make only one wish,
and say it loud and clear
so they can hear it.
We have lovely, bright moonlight tonight.
What are you thinking about for so long?
I can only make one wish,
so I don't know what to write.
You have that many wishes?
Maybe you're actually pretty greedy.
"Greedy"?
It's just that
I've never made a wish before.
What is it?
We should release the lantern soon.
Just give me a rough idea.
The thing is
I feel like
this is actually me being greedy.
I already have more than I could ask for.
So I was just going to leave it at that.
I'm not even sure
if I should wish for this.
Are you talking about your nosiness?
No, I'm not.
You are.
If you're going to wish to be even nosier,
put the brush down.
It's my wish.
Don't be so nosy.
Don't look.
I won't.
You're really wishing hard.
You can tell me now.
I'm sure I can grant your wish faster.
What? Did you see my wish?
No, I didn't.
So it's really something I can do?
No, it's not.
You have nothing to do with it.
I don't believe you.
What is it?
Is there another corrupt official?
No.
Is someone sick?
Is someone starving?
No!
My lord.
I put two winter clothes in your bag.
Thank you.
Where have you been at this hour?
I met someone I know
to ask for something important.
You must be tired.
You should get some sleep soon
before the trip tomorrow.
Eun-jo…
you held on well.
It's nothing.
I missed it.
The animals must have sensed
your procession and run away.
Let's go back to the palace--
Don't even utter a word about the palace
until I hunt a tiger.
- Keep chasing it!
- Yes, Your Majesty.
Father, I'm so exhausted.
We still have a long way to go to Namwon.
Father,
do I really have to go?
Stop complaining and follow me.
Eun-jo!
Coming!
Lady Hae-rim?
To the dispensary?
Where is Hong-si?
She's been on sick leave for a while now.
How would I know about
some sick court lady?
I'm sure you do.
Because that court lady is the woman
you said you would never forget.
Is she from a noble family?
Is her family respectable?
Are they well-off?
Where she is
isn't your main concern, is it?
If the answer to any of that is no,
I don't care where she is.
She already rejected me long ago.
What? Rejected?
What could possibly the reason?
Who would reject a face like yours?
Who dares reject my son?
Where is she? Lead the way.
Now you want to know where she is?
Are you thinking of leaving Joseon
because of Hong-si?
Does Hong-si know?
I will just disappear.
Why would you do that?
If I say goodbye to her,
I will want to stay with her.
And if that happens,
I know I can't stop myself.
I will cling to her
and make a nuisance of myself.
Then she will have to reject me
once again.
I can't make her say something
so painful for her.
If that's your decision,
you shall leave as soon as possible.
I've already packed my bag.
I'm leaving today.
You and His Highness?
All those coincidences
were set up by the elders.
Because that's the kind of marriage
the elders want.
But His Highness does not want it.
That's why he said he was leaving.
Leave?
Where?
That, I don't know.
I've been only talking about myself.
Tell me about you, Physician Hong.
Why was your marriage broken off?
Well…
My lord--
Eun-jo!
Is that…
This is Gil-dong's arrow?
Maybe someone's pretending to be him.
Grand Prince Dowol destroyed
all the evidence linked to Gil-dong.
I'm sure.
Young Master!
The lord sent an urgent letter
from the Royal Villa.
Hong Eun-jo.
Eun-jo.
Do you know him?
I think he's my Young Master.
Eun-jo!
Eun-jo.
I brought Father with me.
You're a physician, right?
Have a look at him.
I don't know why,
but he hasn't said a word the whole way.
I must've done something wrong.
Eun-jo.
My lord.
Who?
Lord Hong Min-jik--
No, the other one.
His Majesty.
So you're saying
my brother…
His Majesty
has hunted
Lord Hong.
You seem tired.
Rest well.
And don't worry about a thing.
There will be no pain…
where you are now.
Father, you should wake up now.
We should keep going.
We have a long way to go.
Father, please wake up.
Where are you going?
We must prepare a funeral.
Just cry.
I must find an embalmer and get a coffin.
There's so much to be done.
The Chief Secretary sent us a letter.
He said to make
all the preparations for the funeral.
It's my lord's funeral.
This is something I have to do myself.
Help my Young Master instead.
He can be pretty clumsy.
Father!
Can you move any faster?
His Majesty wishes to return
to his chambers at once.
Yes, Your Majesty!
Yes, Young Master.
My brother allowed
my family and our slaves
to come and help as well.
By the way, I haven't seen Eun-jo around.
Has she not come back yet?
Eun-jo…
you held on well.
If what I think happens,
not only Eun-jo,
but her entire family will be executed.
We must not let that happen. Never.
Hong Eun-jo! Snap out of it!
If you want to die, die alone.
He jumped in to stop it.
Return!
Pay your respects with utmost sincerity.
Move out!
For now, Lord Hong's family
are the prime suspects.
Find evidence of the murder!
It was me.
How long have I been here?
I must see him.
Subtitle translation by Sunyoung Baek